Guide to the Baseball records, 1933-[ongoing]
Duke University. University Archives
Baseball records 1933-[ongoing]
Duke University. University Archives
Duke University. Sports Information Office.
12.8 linear feet Extent: 13,100 Items
The Sports Information Office provides information about Duke athletics to the media. They also facilitate press interviews with Duke athletes and coaches. The collection includes clippings, press releases, statistics, rosters, programs and press brochures/media guides about the baseball team at Duke University. The material ranges in date from 1933-ongoing.
uabaseball
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Provenance
The Baseball records were received by the University Archives as a transfer over time.
Historical Note
The Sports Information Office provides information about Duke athletics to the media. They also facilitate press interviews with Duke athletes and coaches. For many years, the Sports Information Office has maintained records, photographs and other material about Duke athletic teams.
Collection Overview
The collection includes clippings, press releases, statistics, rosters, programs and press brochures/media guides about the baseball team at Duke University. There are files regarding the freshman (junior varsity) baseball team, The Big Four and ACC Tournaments, the Alumni baseball game played on September 27, 1986, and a compilation of Duke University players that went on to play in the Major Leagues (compiled 1989). The material ranges in date from 1933-ongoing.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Duke University. Sports Information Office; Duke University -- Baseball -- History -- 20th century; Duke University -- Sports
Related Material
Non-Revenue Sports Records.
University Archives, Duke University.
Basketball Records.
University Archives, Duke University.
Football Records.
University Archives, Duke University.
Athletic Dept. Records.
University Archives, Duke University.
Scrapbooks.
University Archives, Duke University.
Photograph Collection.
University Archives, Duke University.
Photographic Negative Collection.
University Archives, Duke University.
Chanticleer Photograph Collection.
University Archives, Duke University.
Athletic Council Records.
University Archives, Duke University.
Athletics Reference Collection.
University Archives, Duke University.
Contents of Collection
- Yearly Files, 1933-[ongoing], 18 Boxes
  The Yearly files contain clippings, press releases, statistics, rosters, and programs about the baseball team at Duke University.
  - 1933-1939 (Box 1)
  - 1945-1947 (Box 2)
  - 1950-1956 (Box 3)
  - includes Dixie Baseball Classic, 1955
  - 1957-1961 (Box 4)
  - 1962-1969 (Box 5)
  - 1970-1979 (Box 6)
  - 1981-1984 (Box 7)
  - includes Pan American Games Baseball tryout, October 23-24, 1982
  - 1984-1987 (Box 8)
  - includes Alumni baseball game, September 27, 1986
  - 1988-1990 (Box 9)
  - includes a compilation of Duke University players that went on to play in the Major Leagues
  - 1991-1992 (Box 10)
  - 1993-1994 (Box 11)
  - 1994-1995 (Box 12)
  - 1996 (Box 13)
  - includes USA Baseball Team Tour - Commemorative Yearbook
  - 1997 (Box 14)
  - 1998-1999 (Box 15)
  - 1999-2000 (Box 16)
  - 2000 (Box 17)
  - 2000-2001 (Box 18)
- Press Brochures/Media Guides, 1972-[ongoing], 1 Box
  - 1972-1982; 1988-1993; 1995-1997; 2000; 2002-2007 (Box 19)